I have two amazing guests and I think
you're going to love both of them. You
know Brendan from our previous projects
and you definitely know John from CIA
Declassified. So today we're going to
talk about um some weird phenomenas,
anomalies, technology, all of the best
stuff that you asked for will be
discussed today. So let me introduce
Brandon Fugal, an author of the whole
show or you produce it?
>> Yes. So, I'm not only the owner of
Skinwalker Ranch and have owned it since
April of 2016.
>> That's right. when I acquired it from
the elusive billionaire Robert Bigalow.
But uh I'm also the executive producer
and creator of the hit uh docue series
The Secret of Skinwalker Ranch as well
as the spin-off series which is called
Beyond Skinwalker Ranch which is
currently airing episodes every Tuesday
night uh 8 um uh 7 central on History
and all of the the other platforms,
Amazon, uh Hulu,
>> Apple TV. So, we have been excited to
unveil to the public the progress of our
ongoing scientific investigation of what
many regard as the most scientifically
studied paranormal hotspot on the
planet. It was part of a Pentagon-f
funded black budget program for a number
of years with the federal government as
a result of reports and evidence that
there was a high frequency of UFO
sightings, bizarre cattle mutilations,
electromagnetic anomalies, and other
phenomena. you know, they locked the the
property down and and as of today,
almost 30 years later, uh it remains
under armed surveillance 24/7, 365 days
a year. And I have the privilege of
being the steward and the owner of this
very unique piece of property. I am also
the chairman of Collier's
International's Inner Mountain region
which is the largest commercial real
estate operating company in the market
and uh am involved in a number of other
ventures and projects that have
absolutely nothing to do with the
>> ranch
>> with the paranormal [laughter] and these
topics but it's a thrill to be with you.
>> Thank you so much. Yeah, most people
don't know that you are actually a very
accomplished businessman. They know you
from the Skinwalker range but not that
and you had the empire before, right?
real estate empire way before you
acquired the ranch.
>> Yeah. I had no desire to ever reveal my
identity to the public as the owner of
this property. I represent hundreds of
prominent commercial real estate
projects in the inner mountain region.
Um own projects myself and I frankly did
not want my identity or my reputation
associated with these topics to be
candid. But uh you know four years into
owning it secretly and funding it with
millions of dollars out of my own
pocket, I was essentially Jedi mind
tricked by the History Channel and
producers to um go public and to allow a
docu series for the first time ever uh
ever uh to allow a docuer effort to come
in behind the gates and to document the
very real ongoing investigation that
continues to build momentum to this
Okay.
>> Crazy.
>> Wow.
>> John, you are a former CIA agent,
officer, I should say. And uh you know,
the CIA never gets involved with these
cases, right? Rarely.
>> Rarely. Rarely. And the involvement has
been historical.
>> All right. Well, first I want to start
with our personal experiences before we
dive into actual like, okay, what's
going on here? Right. So, you had a good
story and I want Brendan to hear because
[laughter]
>> I like to think I'm I'm the one of the
most rational people that I know. Right.
[laughter]
>> Same. I'm with you.
>> Yeah. Right. We're just
>> just two guys.
>> We're just trying to conduct business
and [laughter] operate within a world
that seems to have physical laws that
are easily understood.
>> That's right.
>> That's right. And uh
>> every 10 years or so, scientists say,
you know what, Einstein was right about
and then they tell us one of Einstein's
theories.
>> Right.
>> Well, when I was 17 years old, my my mom
and dad bought a restaurant in a
neighboring town in western Pennsylvania
in Amish country, western Pennsylvania.
And so my dad and I used to work
midnight shift on the weekends and uh we
would drive from our home in Newcastle,
Pennsylvania through Amish country to
Sharon, Pennsylvania. It was about 20
miles and it's very very dark in Amish
country. They don't use electricity. And
so one Friday night at 10:30, I'm
talking about 1981,
I was 17 years old, and we're driving up
Route 60 north, and we see a brilliant
flash of white light. And we both look
up in the sky. There's a second flash
and then a third flash and then this
orange trapezoid just lit up in the
shape that you would say, you know, is
stereotypical of a report of some kind
of flying disc.
>> Yeah. A UFO.
>> A UFO. We pulled over to the side of the
road. I said to my dad, "What is that?"
He said, "I don't know." So, we got out
of the car. We're standing there just
staring at it. It's hovering, not making
any sound at all. A guy pulls up behind
us. He gets out of his car and says,
'What is that?
>> Yeah.
>> My dad said, 'I don't know. And then it
just went
at this fantastic speed.
>> Yeah.
>> Unlike anything I had ever seen before
and it just vanished just like that. We
stood there for a while thinking, is it
going to come back?
>> You know, is it going to do something,
>> right?
>> And then finally, we got in the car and
drove away. And I said to my father,
should we call somebody? Should we like
call the cops or something?
>> Yeah.
>> And he said to say what? We saw a flying
saucer and it flew away.
>> Yeah.
>> They'll think we're nuts. So, we didn't
tell anybody until we told my mom the
next day. But I I'll never forget it as
long as I live.
>> Oh my goodness. So, you're you're uh not
just uh someone who has been brave
enough to address these topics. You are
an experiencer yourself. You've
experienced it.
>> Yeah. I hear some other people's u uh
stories and experiences and I think, "Oh
my goodness." No, mine's nothing like
like theirs. Mine's not as exciting or
as revoly, but it was enough to burn a
place in my memory,
>> you know, for good.
>> Well, I'd have to disagree. The fact
that it wasn't just you that you had you
had witnessed, was it multiple
witnesses?
>> Yeah, there were three of us.
>> Um, it's very similar to my own
experience. You know, I bought the
ranch, Skinwalker Ranch, as a skeptic.
>> I had gone through a faith crisis of
sorts in my life, and I had grown very
skeptical of any claims dealing with the
paranormal
>> or the fringe. And I believed at that
point in time that there was a natural
prosaic explanation for for anything
that was supposedly strange. And when
the opportunity to buy the ranch was
presented to me, I uh was very
transparent with those who u who
introduced the opportunity to me and
even Mr. Bigalow and let them know I I
fully believed that there was a natural
explanation and that I was going to
quickly debunk
>> the claims with my own team of
scientists. And for 6 months I owned the
property and I myself flying in every
month in my helicopter didn't see or
feel anything unusual.
>> Interesting. It just seemed like a
strikingly beautiful diverse backdrop in
the middle of this Uenta basin that is
surrounded by thousands of acres of
Indian tribal land. But 6 months into
it, I had an experience much like you. I
was hosting a uh a visiting uh
physician, a doctor, a scientist who had
worked at Area 51 whose number one item
on his bucket list was to visit
Skinwalker Ranch. And he'd been denied
by the previous owner, Mr. Bigalow the
opportunity and and I had I had approved
his uh his coming to visit under the
condition that he would keep my identity
confidential and sign the the reg was a
you know confidentiality agreements and
liability waiverss. Well, that day
changed everything for me on that day
which was October 14th of 2016.
Uh I went from being a skeptic to not
just a believer but like you an
experiencer.
after witnessing electromagnetic
anomalies, equipment malfunction, even
our smartphones all drained from 80% to
zero within a matter of minutes and and
one person was rendered uh completely
cat catatonic um during the visit, an
attending security officer as we were
driving across the ranch to retrieve our
smartphones hours into the visit. Uh,
the gentleman in the back of this
openair Polaris UTV Ranger that I was
driving started shouting, "Stop the
vehicle." And I looked back at him and
he was waving his arms up in the air and
I thought, "What what is he talking
about?" And as I brought that vehicle to
an abrupt stop and there was dust flying
everywhere. I looked where he was
pointing right up ahead. Right ahead of
us above this messa plateau that runs
the entire expanse of the property east
west was a silver disc-like object. A
4050 foot long silver grayish disc-like
object that was about 100 ft above the
mesa in broad daylight
>> right above us. And we were all sitting
there pointing at it in awe. And within
seconds it changed position. and it
darted to the left.
>> See, they defy the laws of physics.
>> It was in the blink of an eye. It could
change position. Seconds later, it
dropped to what appeared to be a low
hover above the ran above the ranch mesa
there. Few seconds later, after we all
expressed our continued shock, it darted
to the right. And then within moments,
it was gone. In the blink of an eye, it
either darted off at some mock 100 at
some speed that uh
>> that would be difficult to
to quantify or it just blinked out of
this reality or was able to cloak its
identity. But it was gone. The entire
incident which changed my entire world
view in that moment and took me from
being a skeptic to an experiencer was
all of 20 seconds.
>> But it was life-changing. From that
point forward, I had to either
acknowledge the reality
that there's more at play in our in our
world than meets the eye, or I could
deny it and simply ignore it and move on
and pretend that it didn't happen. And
I,
>> as as you've seen, I I ended up doubling
down, spending millions of dollars. And
from that point forward, I began using
science and technology
uh to monitor and document the reality
of the phenomena at this very strange
512 acre assemblage.
>> And like you, it just it was a
life-changing experience. And you know,
I didn't meet any little green men that
came out of the or anything like that,
but
>> unfortunate, [laughter]
>> but I have to tell you, it was
undeniable. and with multiple witnesses,
>> right,
>> who I had never met before that day.
>> And that morning, they had actually the
two security officers had expressed
their skepticism. I asked them, "Do you
believe in UFOs? Do you do you believe
that there's any credibility?" And the
two gentlemen who were accompanying the
doctor both smiled and shook their heads
and said, "No, we don't think there's
anything to it, but we're here to
maintain safety and to make sure
everything goes well." Those gentlemen
were just as in shock as I was.
>> And so to have multiple witnesses,
>> electromagnetic anomalies, equipment
malfunction, an acute medical episode
occur that very afternoon.
>> Oh my.
>> And rapid battery depletion that all
preceded this life-changing event. Uh
it's undeniable the reality
that our skies are being visited, our
airspace is being violated by craft,
objects of unknown origin using advanced
physics and propulsion technology that
defy any conventional explanation is an
absolute reality. And anyone who would
deny it now, I just saw the recent Wall
Street Journal article which was
laughable, which was the most stupid,
insane thing that I've ever seen. if
anyone believes.
>> Could you tell us what was that about
it? Like
>> oh well recently this this is current
current events. Last week, the Wall
Street Journal came out with an article
uh long um piece that essentially said
that oh that that the the government has
come out and that certain individuals
have said that this was all part of a
SCOP, a psychological operation and that
it was part of a hazing process going
back decades um where the government was
staging and showing what they purported
to be evidence to just simply trick or
fool or haze these um pilots and
military officers and that the entire
UFO phenomena they're saying is is
nothing more than just a government scop
which is the biggest the government.
>> No, [laughter]
>> it's the biggest bunch of
>> They're they're lying. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I'll tell you when I was a little
kid
um my father's cousin owned a restaurant
in Alexandria, Virginia, and we used to
go down every summer and visit with the
relatives. Well, the owner's son had a
best friend who was an F-18 pilot
>> in Norfick, Virginia. And I remember as
clearly as the day is, that he said very
casually, and this had to be 197,
I'm going to say six or 77. He said that
as an F-18 pilot, they see these things
all the time. He said there's a standard
operating procedure where they document
the sighting.
>> It's classified and then they send it
into the Pentagon where it just sits in
some database somewhere. And he said you
get used to it except when you see them
come out of the water.
>> He said that that would always panic him
because he didn't know if it had spotted
him and was coming out of the water. It
went down to take a sample of the water.
It's living underneath the water,
>> right?
>> He said, but he and the every other
pilot would document every single one of
these sightings. And we now know thanks
to these wellplaced Pentagon leaks from
what, two, three years ago.
>> Y
>> that they were all seeing these things
and they were all documented.
Absolutely.
>> Why weren't it why weren't they coming
out though? This is where people I'm a
skeptic still despite all I believe you
all. I understand. You know what I mean?
>> I was a skeptic too. I thought it was
all baloney myself. That's the problem
with me. I I It's my problem.
>> But okay, all these pilots, right? Come
out. You blew the whistle on Bush and
torture techniques of the CIA. By the
way, he is brave when as you said.
>> Yeah. It takes courageous individuals to
to come forward
>> at the risk of their reputations, their
careers.
>> Why do they do it? That's my question.
All of them see it.
>> Because it comes down to integrity.
Either you're going to acknowledge and
you're going to
>> to be honest
>> in what you know, what you have
witnessed to be true or you simply are
going to
>> essentially be asked to be public
plugged back into the matrix. It's kind
of like that that movie The Matrix,
which I love, which has become a key
part of pop culture history, where
people,
>> you know, there's a certain individual
cipher who ended up
>> in the middle of the show. um betraying
his his associates, including Keanu
Reeves character, you know, Neo, where
he he basically said, "Look, I just plug
me back in.
>> I I don't want to know reality. I don't
care. Plug me back in. Make me make me
someone famous, like an actor or
something." Yeah. And and it was a
really it was a I'm wildly paraphrasing,
but I think most of the general public
when it comes down to it, as much as
they may be curious about these topics
>> and they might may find them
entertaining in the same way that we go
to the megaplex to see a movie on the
weekend and we like to be entertained,
the reality is people do not
feel comfortable with
with really addressing topics that
challenge their worldview or their
paradigm.
>> I think that's exactly right. At the end
of the day, if anything, and that
includes military personnel, that
includes um our most decorated pilots,
>> law enforcement. When when these people
are faced with the reality of whether
they are willing to go public with what
they know to be true or whether they
want to simp essentially be plugged back
into the matrix
>> and make sure that they get their 401k
that they they have enough to take their
families to Disneyland once a year
>> and to be able to retire with their with
their gold watch and be able to have
time with their grandkids. Most people
do not want to put their reality in
jeopardy over acknowledging these
topics. And I don't know that I blame
them. I can't blame them because these
these topics are sobering.
uh the reality that we aren't alone in
the universe,
that there may be not only worlds of
that number, but we may live in a cosmic
zoo
>> and be part of a very complex
>> experiment
>> is understandably terrifying to most
people and most people can't handle it.
>> They can't handle the truth. kind of
like Jack Nicholson's iconic character
as Colonel Jessup in a few good men
where he where you know Tom Cruz's
grandstanding is lieutenant caff
[laughter]
>> and and Jessup you know played
masterfully by um Jack Nicholson says
you can't handle the truth that the
reality is I don't believe most of the
public
>> can handle the truth
>> and that's why there is so much
disinformation
that's why there is an active effort
to to discredit these topics
>> and and that's been
the
rumored uh position of the Pentagon for
many many decades
>> that the public can't handle the truth.
>> No, it's destabilizing.
>> It's destabilizing. It would lead to
panic
>> and so it's best not to allow the truth.
>> In a way, they are right. Look what
happened during COVID. I mean, we were
out of freaking toilet paper.
>> Yeah.
>> And people were storing milk. Milk.
Milk. It's going to go bad.
>> Well, what are you doing?
>> Everyone was hiding in their basements
hoarding water, toilet paper, and
watching Tiger King
>> and not questioning the science. We all
essentially were just
>> trying to get through
>> that period of time, which was really um
tumultuous.
>> Can you imagine
>> for some people the reality that we're
not alone could perhaps I think have a
destabilizing impact? I don't know.
Well, I I've had my own experiences, but
I remember thinking that exact thing
when everything was happening to me
>> and thinking, "Oh my god, oh my god,
they're always here. They've seen
everything. They're they're with us."
And just that thought alone
>> was like shattering to me. I panicked.
>> Yeah.
>> But Yeah.
>> And that we're not in control. I I'll
tell you the most sobering thing,
>> the most humbling realization
with owning Skinwalker Ranch is learning
that we're not in control.
>> See, that really bothers me because I'm
a control freak. I Everything in my life
should be controlled by me. So, you know
what I mean? Like, how
>> I'm not okay with that.
>> We got to We got to send them to Lizzy,
[laughter]
>> right? I'm not okay with that at all. So
okay well um let's for people who you
know have ton of questions I think we
owe them to to discuss everything. So
you kind of answered the question
already about the government but I was
going to say you know you worked for
like how many years now um before you
retired and do you think that there
could be a slight chance slight chance
that uh we are seeing our own
technologies just I mean we talked about
DARPA you you probably know DARPA
absolutely
>> yeah like I mean they are 30 years ahead
>> well Lockheed skunk works Northrup it's
a fact that there are advanced aerospace
programs that have been in existence for
shady years give or take
>> and those programs are in many cases
they're what they call special
compartmented access programs.
>> Um there is a national security
imperative associated with our defense
and with protecting advanced
technologies and and making sure that
our way of life, our democracy is kept
safe. And I understand the need for
secrecy. Um the challenge is when when
you see things that are so far beyond
>> our capabilities or our current
understanding of physics. Mhm.
>> And even though
President Eisenhower warned of a
military-industrial complex and the rise
of that military-industrial complex and
and secrecy involved with that, um I I
happen to believe in my interactions
with high ranking officials that these
topics even today remain a great
mystery. and
disturbing to many people because I
don't believe that even the government
has all the answers relative to the
origin or the agenda associated with
what we're seeing. You'd mentioned USOs,
unidentified submerged objects. You look
at, you know, objects and phenomena,
aerial phenomena of unknown origin that
are that are in, you know, that are
having encounters with our most
celebrated
>> sophisticated. Yeah, that's right. And
and how do we account for sightings that
go back literally to the 4th century?
There are ancient writings that that
describe these things. You know, a ship
crossing uh the sky in ancient Egypt,
>> chariots of the fire,
>> right? Chariots of fire.
>> That one was on iaska. I don't know.
[laughter]
>> Maybe. Maybe. Although, you know, even
with the ranch.
>> Yeah. One of the surprising aspects of
our investigation was was really
documenting incidents that go back to
the 1930s
relative to bizarre cattle mutilations.
I mean, even the original homesteaders
>> in interviewing their families have come
forward finally
>> with the reality that they were
experiencing strange phenomena and their
own cattle were were being surgically
mutilated, dissected, drained of their
blood. And this goes back to the 30s.
You can't tell me that the government
had a sophisticated
covert program
>> to cover. I mean, we're talking about,
you know, one of the most, if not the
most
>> disturbing unsolved crime spree in the
United States history. Over 10,000
incidents.
>> It was not just the US, as I understand,
right? It was outside of the US. But at
least in the United States, we keep
records and we
>> we have law enforcement that come
forward. But even in the last week,
>> we've seen signs posted by officials
across the basin
offering a $20,000 reward to anyone who
has information leading to the
apprehension of whoever is behind these
very disturbing events that continue to
take place. It's not only surrounding
and involving Skinwalker Ranch,
>> but it's the entire submarket area.
>> You know, I wondered too when the first
when I first heard about Skinwalker
Ranch years ago, I wondered, well, I
maybe it's it's some kind of weird
electromagnetic, you know, something
that's phenomenon that's close to the
surface. That's that's great.
>> Geology, there's got to be a natural
explanation.
>> But electromagnetic fields don't dissect
cattle. No. And and they don't they
don't render um equipment completely
worthless or malfunctioning,
>> right?
>> Put people into catatonic states. and
and frankly um the diversity of
phenomena and the credibility of the
witnesses and the data
>> the hard data derived from the research
activities and investigation under my
watch over the last 8 n years is
it's unimpeachable. I mean, anyone who
does their due diligence has to stand
back and acknowledge that
>> there there's not only unidentified
arrow phenomena that defies any national
explanation, but there are these other
there are these other events, some of
which people would characterize as
poltergeist like events,
>> right?
>> You we have this thing called the
hitchhiker effect. I don't know if
you've heard of this.
>> Oh, yeah. The one that you walk away
with some dark entity. Uh like it's
weird.
>> Yeah. Not only have we had members of
our team and visitors, visiting
scientists and officials that have ended
up in the hospital with mysterious
illnesses and injuries. But we've also
had individuals leave the ranch and upon
leaving the ranch experience in their
own homes disturbing phenomena. Some of
them call it demonic. Some of them have
no other way to describe it other than
poltergeistike activity. but strange
phenomena, dark forces in many cases
that follow them home. They call the
hitchhiker effect that um that is
another element to the phenomena
>> and what we are documenting with a
datadriven approach.
>> Uh my principal investigator and chief
scientist Eric Bard often says we are
not led by an inherited narrative or
anecdotal accounts. We're led by the
data with respect to our investigation.
And I think taking a datadriven approach
with a diversity of professionals
>> from all sorts of different disciplines
and backgrounds is going to help us get
to the bottom of it.
>> Are there any other hot spots like what
you see at Skinwalker Ranch elsewhere
around the world?
>> Absolutely there are. There are other
places of uh of interest. In fact, we've
been investigating it in my spin-off
series Beyond Skinwalker Ranch, which is
also a hit on history that is airing on
Tuesday nights as well, where we've gone
nationwide and even started um
documenting incidents in places globally
that are exhibiting similar phenomena
that have similar claims.
>> Could you name a few?
>> Oh, yeah. I mean, you have uh Bradshaw
Ranch, uh Mount Wilson Ranch in Nevada,
which was also owned by Robert Bigalow.
this seriously.
>> What was wrong with Beagle going after
the '90s
>> and you you take um Mount Wilson and all
of the reports very similar to
Skinwalker Ranch and as we've gone in to
investigate whether there is any
validity to strange phenomena,
electromagnetic anomalies,
>> we've unearthed a whole underground
system
structures that have been buried.
>> What?
>> Underground [clears throat] structures.
a rail system
>> where whereabouts. Um, this isn't Mount
Wilson in Nevada.
>> Is it from some kind of maybe like old
like either war?
>> Yeah,
>> it is definitely a what I believe to be
a covert military op that was shut down.
We've found completely incinerated hard
drives buried deep beneath the earth as
well as entire vehicles that were buried
and then covered over
>> What kind of vehicles? um
government issue vehicles um uh trucks
and and why the the big question is why
would there be such a cover up? Why are
we finding
this evidence buried? What what what
would be so important as to incinerate
hard drives and then proceed to bury
them underground and then leave the area
uh without any further documentation. So
to to answer your question, yes, there
are other sites of interest, but for
whatever reason, Skinwalker Ranch seems
to be uh one that exhibits the highest
degree, the highest frequency of strange
phenomena. And because it has been under
armed guarded surveillance since 1996,
it's been locked down.
>> It it's kind of the private Area 51
equivalent. It has become over nearly 30
years a living laboratory
>> involving
decades of scientific investigation and
study that is unrivaled and I think
gives us a glimpse into not only the
nature of our world but also whether
consciousness plays a role in some of
this as well.
>> Right.
>> Why did Bigalow sell it? Because he was
very much into this phenomena. If there
was something to it then why did he
decide to sell it?
>> That's a good question. I asked myself
the same question I asked Mr. Bigalow.
Why would you sell him?
>> The answer that I was given at the time,
which was actually very legitimate, was
that he has invested hundreds of
millions of dollars out of his own
pocket into
>> much like you the well, but in his case,
the private space race instead of real
estate and expanding his real estate
empire because he made his money in
hospitality and in developing the budget
suites of America, extended hotel chain.
He has diversified
into the private space race, bought
NASA's space habitats program, the
inflatables program, and has been
positioning himself as the real estate
developer of space.
>> I flew out to Las Vegas and had the
privilege of of uh touring his space
compound.
>> Wow. uh 500,000 square feet
>> of secure buildings that house fullsize
space stations and space habitats that
are being designed and tested for life
safety and for deployment in space. And
at that time when I was looking at
acquiring the ranch, he was working with
Elon Musk and SpaceX
>> on getting his habitats up into orbit to
not only replace the International Space
Station potentially, but establish a
lunar and even a Mars
>> colony. I think that may still be a
reality in the future. So that was the
official the official account and the
official feedback that I received was
that he was he his attention had turned
to other topics and uh but I think in
reality and this is all public domain.
Mr. Bigalow had many, many negative
things happen
>> to him and his family. Uh things that
followed him home to Las Vegas. Um
dark disturbing things um that um
occurred and it's not my place to go
into that detail. Um George Knap and
others have reported on it, but I
believe that he wanted to distance
himself from the ranch and blame the
ranch for a lot of very disturbing
negativity that had occurred in his
personal life. And um as I've tried to
bring him back, you know, the most
recent time several years ago, we hosted
Mr. Bigalow and his uh team of
scientists that had served on the ranch.
I invited them to fly out in my
helicopter or my jet and host them. I
was so
>> excited.
>> Excited and anxious to show what I had
done.
>> Oh, sure.
>> I wanted to show Mr. Bigalow, who I
consider a giant. I consider him a a
courageous individual, an entrepreneur
who really was a trailblazer
>> and and when it comes to these topics, I
mean, there was no one like him that was
willing to engage these topics in the
private sector
>> and I was anxious to show him that I've
created my own NASA mission control
equivalent. I mean, we've instrumented
that property.
>> Well, I've seen your hangers research.
We have a very sophisticated program out
there and Mr. Bigalow had not only zero
interest
>> Oh my gosh.
>> in visiting the ranch ever again, but
was violently opposed.
>> Wow.
>> And I respect that. There are certain
individuals that served under his
ownership that refused to ever set foot
on the ranch ever again.
>> Wow.
>> And in full transparency,
I'll never allow my own children to set
foot on the property. Uh, Bigalow sold
the property to me both out of um an e
effort to be able to focus all of his
time and attention
>> to the private space race, but also
because I think he had experienced so
much negativity
>> in his personal life and his family had
had such tragedy occur that was in his
view attributed to his ownership of the
ranch that it was time to close that
chapter. I was a skeptic. So I I I
told everyone upfront that I not only
never wanted to to reveal my identity as
the owner. I never wanted my identity to
be involved with these topics, but I
also believe that there was a natural
explanation and that I would ultimately
debunk it. At the time I was on the
board of the National Parks Council of
the Boy Scouts of America. I'm a I'm an
Eagle Scout, have a couple of palms and
was Order of the Arrow if for anyone
who's familiar.
>> That's a big deal. Yeah. And I I
actually thought it would be an
incredible scout camp. It would be
perfect setting for boy scouts and girl
scouts [laughter]
>> and
>> until they have their blood drain.
>> Yeah. Until they end up in the hospital
and you're sued by all of their parents.
Um anyways, I'm sorry to command so much
discussion.
>> It's absolutely interesting. And uh
Okay. Well, let's go into what do you
think these these entities are?
>> What do you think?
>> Yeah.
After
seeing what the likes of the Hubble
Space Telescope have shown us over the
last few years where there are billions,
trillions of of
known galaxies, known galaxies,
>> right?
>> We can't possibly be the only
intelligent life. We just can't be.
>> It it defies logic.
Now,
that life may be a bacterium
or it may be a race that is millions of
years more advanced than we are. We just
don't know. You know, I I'm also very
interested in this uh uh Harvard
University uh professor and
>> Alvi Lo.
>> Ali Lobe. I've had him on my own show a
couple of times. God,
>> this is a serious academic, a serious
researcher,
and he just lays out the data, including
his take from this uh offshore
uh experiment. not even an experiment.
He he went offshore off the coast of
Papa New Guinea
>> and pulled remnants of something off the
floor of the Pacific
>> that is made up of a material not known
to exist on Earth. Now, he said it could
have been some sort of interstellar
meteorite that we've just never seen
before, or it could be
an actual metal that has been fabricated
by an intelligent being. We don't know.
He said they're just the size of BB's.
>> Yeah.
>> And they bear additional um research and
study. But I mean it it you have to
conclude that there's got to be
something out there.
>> Well, the number of exoplanets or
planets that have been identified that
can support life now are so numerous.
>> Oh yes.
>> That [clears throat] it's becoming
actually quite ignorant for anyone to
believe that we're the only intelligent
life in the universe. It's not a
function of or a question of of of if
>> you know there are other worlds that are
populated by intelligence. It's it's
when will we come into contact with them
and do they have the physics
>> the the propulsion capability if you
will to talk in very rudimentary terms
to be able to visit. I think that we've
been visited since the beginning of
time. I I think that the evidence going
back and looking at the ancients and
what they left us and and and a lot of
the uh the accounts that have gone back
thousands of years attest to the fact
that we're not alone.
When asked, you know, I've had a number
of major [snorts] national publications
that have asked me [clears throat] the
the same question. You know, what is
>> what is the origin? What is the origin,
the agenda? And
>> you know, is it beings from other
worlds? Is it interplanetary? Is it
multi-dimensional or interdimensional?
Maybe even time travel or is it
>> I think it's all of them.
>> Angels and demons, right? Is it
>> Do you think our world is kind of their
world and we are the ones that maybe
like
>> that they were here first?
>> Yeah. I mean,
>> or they created
>> I like that smile. What's [laughter]
going on there?
>> Like I said, one of the most humbling
realizations,
>> right? And this isn't just for me, but
my entire team is the fact that
not only are we not alone, but we're not
in control,
>> right?
>> We're dealing with intelligence,
with technology that has the ability to
manipulate spaceime.
>> It has the ability to manipulate closed
systems
and and even consciousness itself. There
is something about Skinwalker Ranch
that is also reflexive or it amplifies
consciousness. What we found when people
enter the property, if they enter with
uh with a spirit of negativity or
contention, we've found through the
data, tracking these visits and these
interactions that often those people
that enter with with that kind of
attitude end up experiencing negativity
or malevolence. Uh
>> so they attract it.
>> Yeah. And and there's a reason why I ask
everyone who enters the property,
whether they're flying in with me via
the helicopter or driving in through the
security gates and being checked in at
the guard shack,
I ask everyone, regardless of their
religious background or their belief
system, please enter with prayer, with a
spirit of reverence and humility,
>> because we're dealing with forces
>> that uh that are powerful.
Okay. So, we are not in control. They
are in control in a way, but they don't
want to show themselves fully, right?
Like they don't want to assimilate with
us apparently like they are kind of
getting us signals or whatever. But the
problem I have with this, if they are so
in control, we went through World War I,
World War II, we are about to go in
World War II.
>> Oh, I hope not.
>> What the heck are they doing then? Are
they just not nice? Do they want to
destroy ours? It's a constant conflict.
>> There was the accounts of them stopping
the um nuclear bombs.
>> Oh, those are rumors. Like what nuclear
bomb?
>> Not really. Those aren't rumors. That
those are documented incidents. And that
is what is so disingenuous about the
recent Wall Street Journal piece, which
was nothing but a hatchet job.
>> Uh that was not honest. Um, anyone who
has done their due diligence on the the
disruption that our military
installations, specifically our nuclear
>> Yeah.
>> assets, our missile silos, have
experienced that involve unidentified
aerial phenomena and those silos being
completely brought offline. Mhm.
>> And the number of witnesses who have
gone on record that have bravely come
forward over decades relative to their
accounts. This isn't about some military
scop or hazing program. This is very
real. This is a national security.
>> I would agree with that. But the issue I
have where were they during Hiroshima
Nagasaki? I mean so many people died.
>> Some people say that they saw
unidentified aerial phenomena during
that event or preceding that event. Um,
>> I think if they made themselves known,
we'd go into panic, right?
>> Well, and there may be a prime directive
in place. It's so funny. I'm I'm more of
a Star Wars guy than a Star Trek guy,
but if you're familiar with the Star
Trek universe
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Um, there is this thing called the Prime
Directive where where, you know, they're
not to meddle with or reveal themselves
free, right? No interference with
civilizations that have yet to to
evolve.
>> Well, let's turn this game. You you
talked about Mars and you talked about
Elon Musk. I'm a huge fan. Well, Elon is
weird.
>> Oh, I'm a huge fan. Talk about
courageous. The greatest entre
entrepreneur
>> um of our time,
>> hands down, perhaps of all time. No
matter what your political
>> positions are. No one can deny the fact
that there has never been an
entrepreneur before him that has has
actually
>> disrupted more sectors of the economy
and brought forward more
transformational
approaches to everything from
>> uh solar
>> to space transit to um
>> to payment processing.
>> Yeah. To um payment process, PayPal.
[laughter]
Um you look at Neurolink.
>> Yeah.
>> Scares the daylights out of me. Me too.
[snorts]
I think it's crazy
>> and and um I mean we live in incredible
times. I mean I think the the rate of
change that we are going to witness over
the course of the next 5 years will
outpace the decades preceding. There's a
>> gentleman you probably have followed him
a futurist named um Kerszswwell
Kerszswwell who who has spoken and
written about the singularity. The
singularity is near and the you know the
point in time that inflection point
where it will be impossible to be able
to distinguish between man or machine.
We're there.
>> You seem excited. I'm not like it scares
me. Soulless machines. I know why you're
excited because you are in this world,
right? So for you it's like more of a
disco. you're you're leading like with a
mind like Elon Musk in a way that okay
this is great for us but we are looking
at it like you know coming from the
government and an investigative
journalist like okay how nefariously you
going to use this because John
knows what our government is capable of
these are the same people that kill
their own citizens when they need to for
greater good so and you know like then
but there's Elon Musk which you know I I
trust Ian I think he means well
>> power to the people I mean I I believe
that disclosure,
>> right,
>> true disclosure is going to come through
the private sector. And that's why I
take my stewardship of Skinwalker Ranch
in these topics very seriously
>> because I don't think you can trust the
the government and and and no offense
because I actually think that there are
incredibly good people, brilliant people
that are involved with public service
that have been involved with our our um
with the CIA, with the FBI, with our
Department of
>> Exactly. my position
>> and and thank goodness we've had those
people that serve our country and
protect democracy. And even though you
have bad actors, and you do have bad
actors,
>> a lot of them,
>> I think that there's reason to rejoice.
You look at our quality of life today
versus 100 years ago. 100 years ago,
people were still making the transition
from horse and buggy
>> to the automobile. Mhm.
>> Our our highway system was barely being
built. I mean, we were just we were just
decades uh from Promontory where they
connected the uh intercontin continental
rail line.
>> That's right.
>> Electricity was a new innovation
electrifying our cities
>> and not universally available.
>> Yeah. You look at today though and you
look at the fact that we all hold the
Library of Alexandria in our pocket. We
hold in our palms
the power of information, of knowledge,
of innovation
that surpasses anything that even our
own my own grandparents and
great-grandparents would have ever
imagined. the ability to transform our
world for the better.
>> For us to join
as a as an interplanetary or or a a uh
space fairing species to to reach beyond
earth to to be able to explore the stars
I think is within our grasp and what it
does
>> is it ensures the survival of humanity
>> and the progression. Mhm. I
>> I think to a degree if these things if
these UFOs if the intelligence behind
the UFO or UAP phenomena was all
malevolent, if we were
>> Oh yeah.
>> If we were slaves, if we were being
basically harvest if we were being
harvested
>> for our souls or for enslavement, I
think there's a good chance we would
have already experienced that. I mean,
they they've already demonstrated that
they have control beyond what we can
imagine. Um I believe
that we do live in a divinely
constructed intelligently designed
reality. I believe that there is a
higher power that there is a there is a
purpose
>> God maybe.
>> I absolutely believe it and I believe
that that divinity that divine force
>> that connects all of us that connects
our collective consciousness to a degree
has
the good of humanity.
>> Can I say something about Elon Musk very
quickly?
>> Yeah, absolutely. Forgive me if you've
heard of this.
>> Yeah, go for it.
>> In 2009,
I had an idea for a television uh a
newsbased television series and I had a
friend who was very active in that world
and I I told him about it. He said, "Oh,
we should pitch it. But you know what?"
He said, "My best friend from high
school was just named the president of
NBC, so let me call him first and we can
pitch it to him." I said, "Great."
My friend Rich calls his friend Ben and
uh Ben says, "Oh, I'm going to be in
Washington. There's a big fundraiser at
the White House and why don't we meet at
this restaurant bar across the street
afterwards?" We said, "Great." He calls
us at 9 to say he's going to be 15
minutes late and do we mind if he brings
a friend? I said, "The more the
marrier." Yeah.
>> He comes at 9:15
and with this guy and uh Rich and Ben
are hugging each other and patting each
other in the back. And then Ben says,
"Uh, this is my friend Elon." I said,
"Hi, Elon. My name's John. Nice to meet
you." We sit down. Rich and Ben are
talking about high school and the girls
they went out with and it was all, you
know, memory lane. I got bored. So I
turned I said, "So Elon, what do you do
for a living?"
And it was like he snapped into
>> reality,
>> a kid.
>> Yeah. And he said, "Oh, I have this
passion for technology and I created
this company called PayPal. And then I
sold it for like a billion dollars. And
then I took the money and I made another
company. I bought a company called
Tesla. And then I made this space
company. And we're going to go to Mars.
And we're going to colonize Mars. and
we're gonna put a bubble with oxygen in
it and people are gonna settle Mars. I
said, "Wait a minute. Wait a minute. Are
you saying you're Elon Musk?"
>> Yeah.
>> And he says, "Yeah." And I said, "The
Thomas Edison of our time."
>> He said, "I guess so." But anyway,
listen. [laughter] We're going to go to
Mars and the first people that are up
there, they're probably not going to
make it, and then others will follow
them, and eventually we're going to
colonize Mars. All night long. That's
all he talked about was Mars. And I
thought, "This guy's somebody special.
This wasn't just a normal guy and this
is before anybody knew who Elon Musk was
in
tech.
>> And but you even look at Jeff Bezos.
Sure.
>> Who has also put a large portion of his
fortune into Blue Origin.
>> That's right.
>> In a race against Elon Musk and and also
to enable space travel.
>> And isn't that kind of competition
wonderful?
>> It's beautiful.
>> It so advances us.
>> It's freaking America at it.
>> Exactly right. But Jeff Bezos in his he
was high school validictorian and in his
high school validator speech you can
this is on the public domain. Guess what
his speech was about and focused on? It
was
>> traveling to the stars. It was about
space colonization.
>> Wow.
>> And moving beyond our current state into
the next frontier. And you look at what
Jeff Bezos is doing. So many others. I
mean Paul Allen, the late Paul Allen,
co-founder of Microsoft who who invested
significant resources into this effort.
Richard Branson. Yeah.
>> You know, for all of his showmanship.
>> Yeah. I mean, you look at what Virgin
has done in order to at least electrify
um uh imaginations and uh and you have
an unmatched
degree of private sector investment.
If it wasn't for SpaceX and Elon Musk
and his risktaking, we would still be
dependent on the Russians,
>> yes,
>> to get to the International Space
Station. Let everyone ponder that for a
moment that the last 15 years since the
space shuttle program was completely
dismantled,
we would have been completely 100% at
the mercy of the Russians,
>> who we should give a huge credit to.
>> Yeah. because they actually pioneered
pretty much everything when it gets to
space. They were the ones to send first
uh dog.
>> Hey, quit it.
>> No, [laughter]
they
sputnick. Well, you look at the space
race. You look at
>> human man, woman, like all of them. That
That's Russia.
>> Oh, Sputnik. Well, you look at what a
fire it built. What a catalyst.
>> And what a call to action. You look at
President John F. Kennedy and uh and his
imperative, his call to action
>> the decade.
>> Yeah.
>> And but it takes it takes a diversity of
individuals with resources and vision.
Even Howard Hughes, you remember the
late Howard Hughes?
>> Sure.
>> Who ended up kind of, you know, dying
>> just in a dark dingy hotel room in Las
Vegas. But that that individual Howard
Hughes to a degree who is a precursor to
Elon Musk
>> indeed
>> funded more innovation into everything
from medical to our satellite our
>> GPS aerospace still exists.
>> Yeah. And
>> what an incredible
uh time to live in. What an incredible
um momentum that we are witnessing. So I
yes I choose to be optimistic about the
future. I think that we have good people
that want to see our world improved.
Um that are trying to work together and
even competitively against each other in
order to push us push boundaries. And I
choose that narrative over the
Terminator that cyberdine systems is
going to ultimately annihilate us and
render human species
>> completely u irrelevant. Move. Mhm.